Listen to a presentation on the five most frequently visited museums of Australia.
First, you have some time to look at questions 11 to 15.
Now listen to the first part of the talk and answer questions 11 to 15.
Good evening and thank you Mr. Livingstone for inviting me to speak before you all.
To all of you, thank you for being here.
As you know, my name is Dr. Harold Kramer.
I'm the Chief of Operations for the Pacific Museum of Natural History located here in Queensland.
I will be discussing the five most frequently visited museums of Australia.
As you all know, a museum is an institution that houses and showcases collections of artifacts and relics
which are of scientific, artistic, cultural, or historic value and make valuable displays and presentations.
Not only that, museums are places that provide facilities for study,
whether it's in the realm of science, history, aesthetics, or a combination of all three.
The artifacts, models, displays, and other presentations are open for viewing by people through exhibitions.
It is a general notion that museums are visited only by scholars or students.
This notion is unfortunate and archaic because it springs from the misconception that museums are dreary and drab places.
On the contrary, museums can be quite fascinating and intriguing places.
I think you'll be very much surprised to learn how many people visit these institutions annually.
Among these visitors, you will of course find scholars, students, and tourists.
But you will find many, many other people who visit.
Often, you'll find whole families showing up at a museum with the parents explaining that they bring their children
to learn about the world around them or about things from the past.
Others come because by visiting, they learn about new things and have great, fun-filled experiences.
It really is a pleasure to see all these people visit.
It makes the job of working in a museum very fulfilling.
Before you hear the rest of the talk, you have some time to look at questions 16 to 20.
Now listen and answer questions 16 to 20.
Tonight, I'm going to tell you about the top five museums of Australia.
The museums that I'm going to speak about are the National Museum of Australia, Museum of Contemporary Art,
Australian National Maritime Museum, National Sports Museum, and the National Gallery.
After I describe these museums, I will reveal how many have visited them during the summer months this year.
The number will astound you.
We'll begin with the National Museum.
It was established in 1980 and officially opened in Canberra.
It preserves the social history of the Aborigines and traces the events that have shaped the nation through the ages.
It houses the world's largest collection of Aboriginal bark paintings and stone tools
and is a delight to archaeologists and those interested in Aboriginal culture.
The Museum of Contemporary Art was founded in 1996 and was created as a permanent institution for contemporary art.
It is located in Sydney and is evolving in exhibiting, interpreting, and collecting contemporary art
from all over Australia and the world.
It is a hub for lovers of modern art.
The Australian National Maritime Museum is located in Sydney
and is visited for its display of ships and submarines that are often docked in the harbour in front of the museum.
It allows visitors to go aboard these vessels and experience life at sea.
It also displays items relating to Australia's dependence on the oceans
and has been open to the public since 1973.
The National Sports Museum is an amazing museum inside the Melbourne Cricket Grounds.
As the name suggests, it keeps a record of the sporting stories from its early beginnings to present times.
Sporting heroes, their achievements, and other memorable sporting moments find a place here.
It was founded in 1969 and includes the Australian Cricket Hall of Fame,
the Australian Racing Museum, and the Sport Australia Hall of Fame.
It also features a large interactive area that is popular with all ages.
The National Gallery, located in Perth, is by far the most famous gallery in all of Australia.
It has extensive displays of western art, beginning from medieval times and stretching to modern art.
It also features eastern art, mostly in the form of traditional art from South and East Asia,
as well as international modern art.
Over the one century of its existence, it has collected and displayed sculptures, paintings, murals, relics, and lots more.
Over the summer this year, these museums witnessed record numbers of visitors.
The National Museum alone received 10,000 visitors.
That is the end of part 2. You now have half a minute to check your answers.
Now turn to part 3.